A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- A Personnel Resources Directory for the Education of Indochinese Refugees: Supplement 2 (Reports 011426-008), 1975 (Box 479)
- Vietnamese Refugee Alert Bulletin: no. 1 (Reports 011426-009), 1975 (Box 479)
- Indochinese Refugee Alert Bulletin, no. 1-10 (Reports 011426-010), 1975-1978 (Box 479)
- Correspondence re: Center for Applied Linguistics publications (Reports 011426-011), 1975 (Box 479)
- Language research in progress: Report 3 (Reports 011426-012), 1966 (Box 479)
- Language research in progress: Report 5 (Reports 011426-013), 1967 (Box 479)
- Language research in progress: Report 8 (Reports 011426-014), 1969 (Box 479)
- Language research in progress: Report 9 (Reports 011426-015), 1969 (Box 479)
- Linguistics in the 1970s (Reports 011426-016), Greenberg, Joseph H. (Joseph Harold), 1915-2001; McQuown, Norman A.; Halle, Morris; Labov, William (Box 479)
- Styles of learning among American Indians: An outline for research: Report and recommendations of a conference held at Stanford University, August 8-10 (Reports 011426-017), 1969 (Box 479)
- Planning conference for a bilingual kindergarten program for Navajo children: Conclusions and recommendations, October 11-12 (Reports 011426-018), 1968 (Box 479)
- Colloque International sur les Problems des langues secondes (Reports 011426-019), 1966 (Box 479)
- Second national conference of EPDA bilingual education project directors: Preparation and certification of teachers of Bilingual-Bicultural Education, Albuquerque, New Mexico, February 13-15 (Reports 011426-020), 1975 (Box 479)
- Conference proceedings, with a paper on Sociolinguistic Surveys: State of the Art. International conference on the methodology of sociolinguistic surveys, Montreal, Quebec, Canada, May 19-21 (Reports 011426-021), 1975 (Box 479)
- A survey of the current study and reaching of North American Indian languages in the United States and Canada (Reports 011426-022), 1975; Martin, Jeanette P. (Box 479)
- Recommendations of language policy in Indian education (Reports 011426-023), 1973 (Box 479)
- Inventory of projects and activities in reading and English, no. 1-4 (Reports 011426-024), 1966 (Box 480)
- Selected list of instructional materials for English as a second language: Audio-Visual aids (Reports 011426-025), 1974 (Box 480)
- Guidelines for the preparation and certification of teachers of bilingual/bicultural education (Reports 011426-026), 1974 (Box 480)
- Teachers of English to speakers of other languages: Report to NACTEFL, October 24 (Reports 011426-027), 1975 (Box 480)
- National Advisory Council on the Teaching of English as a Foreign Language: Decisions of Meeting, no.6 (Reports 011426-028), 1965 (Box 480)
- TOEFL: Testing of English as a foreign language (Reports 011426-029), 1965 (Box 480)
- The relationship between TESOL and the Center for Applied Linguistics (Reports 011426-030), 1972 (Box 480)
- Teaching English to speakers of other languages: United States activities: 1967 (Reports 011426-031), 1968 (Box 480)
- Report on Center for Applied Linguistics international activities (Reports 011426-032), undated (Box 480)
- Language in Education Committee: Preliminary report (Reports 011426-033), 1969 (Box 480)
- John Lotz: a personal memoir (Reports 011426-034), undated; Sebeok, Thomas A. (Thomas Albert), 1920-2001 (Box 480)
  Applied linguistics; Language and education; Education, Bilingual -- United States; Language and languages -- Study and teaching
- On social, regional, and age variation in black English (Reports 011426-035), 1974; Troike, Rudolph (Box 480)
- One view of continuing functions in English language education a the Center for Applied Linguistics (Reports 011426-036), undated; Hayes, Alfred S. (Box 480)
- Strengthening UCLA's training, research, and service resources in the teaching of English as a second language (Reports 011426-037), 1973; Ohannessian, Sirarpi (Box 480)
- Retrospective survey: The University of the West Indies (Reports 011426-038), undated; Marckwardt, Albert H. (Albert Henry), 1903-1975 (Box 480)
- The Indian language assistance project (Reports 011426-039), 1978 (Box 480)
- Language policy for Indian education (Reports 011426-040), 1973 (Box 480)
- The Sudan: A profile of languages and their use (Reports 011426-041), 1975 (Box 480)
- Indonesia: A profile of languages and their use (Reports 011426-042), 1975 (Box 480)
- Ethiopia: A profile of languages and their use (Reports 011426-043), 1975 (Box 480)
- Peru: A profile of languages and their use (Reports 011426-044), 1975 (Box 480)
- Income, expenditures and general fund projections: Fiscal Year 1972 (Reports 011426-045), 1972-1973 (Box 480)
- Center for Applied Linguistics Annual Report (Reports 011426-046), 1970 (Box 481)
- Progress report on CAL contribution to NCBE operation (Reports 011426-047), 1978 (Box 481)
- Report to the Board of Trustees - December 1973 and (Reports 011426-048), 1973-1974 (Box 481)
- Center for Applied Linguistics: Report on examinations with supplementary information, years ended September 30, 1978 and (Reports 011426-049) (Box 481)
- News clippings and misc. reports, correspondence, etc. re: Center for Applied Linguistics (Reports 011426-050), 1974-1975 (Box 481)
- Ownership alternatives for cable television in the Dayton metropolitan area: Working note, 1971 Nov. (Reports 011427), Baer, Walter S.; Camph, Donald H.; Rand Corporation (Box 481)
  Cable television -- Ohio -- Dayton -- Access; Rand Corporation
- State-tribal relations: handbook (Reports 011428), 1981; Commission on State-Tribal Relations; United States. Bureau of Indian Affairs; William H. Donner Foundation (Box 481)
  "This material is based upon work supported by the Department of Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs, under BIA Grant Number K51C1420G030, Ford Foundation and Donner Foundation." -t.p./cover page
  08150145
  Indians of North America -- Government relations; Indians of North America -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Commission on State-Tribal Relations; United States. Bureau of Indian Affairs; William H. Donner Foundation
- Instructional uses of cable television in Washington, D.C.: draft, 1971 (Reports 011429), Jordan, Paul L.; Rand Corporation; John and Mary R. Markle Foundation; Mitre Corporation (Box 481)
  37 leaves.
  Cable television -- Washington (D.C.); Educational television stations -- Washington (D.C.); Rand Corporation; John and Mary R. Markle Foundation; Mitre Corporation
- Attachments, 1977-80. (Reports 011430), African Training and Research Centre for Women
  Research reports, bibliographies and conference proceedings. This is not a complete collection of ATRCW papers.
  7600464
  1 archives box (5 linear inches containing 9 items).
  Rural women -- Africa; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Employment -- Liberia; Fisheries -- Liberia; Women -- Employment -- Ghana; Women -- Employment -- Kenya; Women -- Employment -- Zambia; Children -- Zambia -- Mortality; Infants -- Zambia; African Training and Research Centre for Women
- Women Workers in Ghana, Kenya, Zambia: A Comparative Analysis of Women's Employment in the Modern Wage Sector (Reports 011430-001), 1979; Akerele, Olubanke (Box 481)
  07600464
  Rural women -- Africa; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Employment -- Africa; United Nations. Economic Commission for Africa
- Broadcasting for the Integration of Women in Development: The ATRCW Perspective (Reports 011430-002), 1977 (Box 481)
- Report of the Second Regional Conference on the Integration of Women in Development, Lusaka, Zambia, 3-7 (Reports 011430-003), 1979 (Box 481)
- Programs for Better Family Living Component, in the United Nations Economic Commission for Africa and Research Centre for Women (ATRCW) of the Social Development Division (Reports 011430-004), 1978 (Box 481)
- Report of the Review Mission, African Training and Research Centre for Women (Reports 011430-005), 1978 (Box 481)
- Women and Development in Africa: An Annotated Bibliography (Reports 011430-006), 1977 (Box 481)
- Law and the Status of Women in Nigeria (Reports 011430-007), 1979 (Box 482)
- Interrelationships among Infant and Childhood Mortality, Socio-economic Factors and Fertility in Zambia: A Case Study of Lusaka and Keembe (Reports 011430-008), undated (Box 482)
- Women and the Fishing Industry in Liberia (Reports 011430-009), 1979 (Box 482)
  Rural women -- Africa; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Employment -- Africa; United Nations
- Report of the Seminar on Rural Development and Women's Employment Problems in Kenya (1981 November 16-21: Nairobi, Kenya) (Reports 011431), 1983; Nigam, S. B. L. (Shyam Behari Lal); Oduor-Otieno, Barrack; Kenya. Ministry of Labour. Division of Manpower Planning and Development; Jobs and Skills Programme for Africa; Seminar on Rural Development and Women's Employment Problems in Kenya (1981 November 1 (Box 482)
  08250361
  118 leaves.
  Seminar on Rural Development and Women's Employment Problems in Kenya (1981 November 16-21: Nairobi, Kenya)
  Women -- Employment -- Kenya; Women in rural development -- Kenya; Unemployment -- Kenya; Underemployment -- Kenya; Migration, Internal -- Kenya; Sociology, Rural -- Kenya; Kenya. Ministry of Labour. Division of Manpower Planning and Development; Jobs and Skills Programme for Africa
- Establishment of planning cells in certain DPAP districts: report of an action research project (Reports 011432), 1983; Mathur, Kuldeep; Gupta, Anil K., 1949-; Indian Institute of Public Administration (Box 482)
  07700190
  41 leaves, 166 pages.
  Regional planning -- India; Drought Prone Areas Programme (India) DPAP
- An evaluation study of the operations of Rural Development Cell (Reports 011433), 1982; Murāri Ballāḷa, Ni.; Ravindranath, K. V. (Box 482)
  07700090
  [3], 61 leaves.
  Rural development projects -- India
- Management education for development: comparative experience in Malaysia, the Philippines, and Thailand (Reports 011434), 1976; Chee, Stephen; Karnjanaprakorn, Choop; Ocampo, Romeo B.; Silverman, Jerry M. (Box 482)
  07300090;06300106
  iv, 370 leaves, tables -- 28 cm.
  Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Malaysia; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Thailand; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Philippines; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Southeast Asia; Education and state; University of the Philippines. College of Public Administration UPCPA; Universiti Malaya; Sathāban Bandit Phatthanabō̜rihānsāt (Thailand)
- Developing a program of public information as graduate education: annual report to the Ford Foundation 1978-1979 1979? (Reports 011435), Green, Thomas F.; Haynes, Emily E. (Box 483)
  Report covers first year of operations of a three-year project.
  07800402
  101 leaves.
  Education -- Aims and objectives -- United States; Education -- Graduate work; Moral education; Competency-based educational tests; Basic education
- Final report to the Ford Foundation: grant no. 825-0804 May 15, 1982--May 15, 1983 1984? (Reports 011436), Savannah Landmark Rehabilitation Project (Box 483)
  Includes 15 photographs.
  08250804
  14 leaves.
  Housing development -- Georgia -- Savannah (Ga.); Housing rehabilitation -- Georgia -- Savannah (Ga.); Savannah Neighborhood Action Projects SNAP; Community Development Block Grant Program (Savannah, Ga.); United States. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development HUD
- Implementation of affirmative action: a preliminary identification of impetus and enabling factors (Reports 011437), 1979; Taylor, Marilyn (Box 483)
  07390804
  18 pages.
  Affirmative action programs -- Virginia -- Arlington
- Computing activities in selected institutions in Indonesia: A report of a consulting trip to Indonesia commissioned by the Ford Foundation (Reports 011438), 1975; Sīsak Čāmō̜nmān (Box 483)
  07290255
  v, 127 leaves.
  Computation laboratories -- Indonesia; Computer engineering -- Indonesia; Computers -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia
- The Arts Income Management System: program summary (Reports 011439), 1985; Theatre Communications Group (Box 483)
  08100509
  v, 148 pages.
  Microcomputers and the arts; Arts -- Management; Arts Income Management System AIMS
- Proposal for Arts Income Management System (Reports 011440), 1981; Arthur Andersen & Co. (Box 483)
- Arts Income Management System: system specifications, July 10 (Reports 011441), 1980; Ziff, Charles E. (Box 483)
  111, 61, [13] leaves.
- Education and employment: Easing the transition from school to work (Reports 011442), 1982; Carol, Joy, 1938- (Box 483, Reel R-9302)
  Includes 6 appendices.
  Vocational education -- United States; Labor supply -- Effect of education on; Youth -- Employment -- Law and legislation -- United States; Unemployment -- United States
- Work, service, and learning: Overcoming deficits with opportunities 198 (Reports 011443), 1982; Berlin, Gordon (Box 483)
  Reviews the accomplishments of two grantees: the Remediation and Training Institute and Public/Private Ventures.
  Poor youth -- Employment -- United States; Poor youth -- Services for -- United States; Socially handicapped youth -- Services for -- United States; Basic education -- United States; Remedial teaching -- United States; Labor supply -- United States; Remediation and Training Institute; Comprehensive Competencies Program CCP; Corporation for Public/Private Ventures
- Cutting through 1986? (Reports 011444), Berlin, Gordon; Sum, Andrew; Taggart, Robert J., 1941- (Box 483)
  Basic education; Competency-based education; Labor supply -- Effect of education on; Youth -- Employment -- United States; Minority youth; Illegitimacy -- United States; Remediation and Training Institute; Ford Foundation. Project on Social Welfare and the American Future
- The "trainee business" phenomenon: Current operations, prospects, and recommendations for Ford Foundation involvement (Reports 011445), 1983; Walker, Gary A.; Grinker, Walker & Associates (Box 483)
  Reviews four trainee businesses: San Francisco Renaissance, Court Employment Project, Advocap, and Freedom Factory. Includes letter from the author to Gordon Berlin and Ellen Potash [Arrick], for whom this report was prepared.
  30, ii leaves.
  Occupational training -- United States; Employees -- Training of -- United States; Manpower policy -- United States; Youth -- Employment -- United States; Small business -- United States; San Francisco Renaissance (Firm); Court Employment Project (New York, N.Y.); Freedom Factory (Cincinnati, Ohio); Advocap (Fond du Lac, Wis.)
- Site visits to urban poverty programs for youth work, service and learning, January 30, 1986. (Reports 011446), Berlin, Gordon (Box 483)
  All sites were in New York City. Includes: essays and supporting documents describing the sites visited.
  Youth -- Employment -- United States; Labor supply -- United States -- Effect of education on; Basic education; Labor service -- United States; Youth Action Program (New York, N.Y.); City Volunteer Corps (New York, N.Y.) CVC; Bank Street College of Education. Basic Skills Academy; Remediation and Training Institute
- Getting credit where credit is due: community development credit unions and the economics of self-help (Reports 011447), 1987; Louis, Errol T. (Box 483)
  60 leaves.
  Community development, Urban -- United States; Credit unions; Small business -- Finance
- Employment and income generation, plant closings and worker ownership: The case for a Foundation role 198 (Reports 011448), 1984; Berlin, Gordon (Box 483)
  Concerned in large part with the activities of Philadelphia Association for Cooperative Enterprise (PACE) and Industrial Cooperative Association (ICA). Includes two appendices;newspaper clippings.
  31 leaves.
  Employee ownership -- United States; Plant shutdowns -- United States; Occupations -- United States; New business enterprises -- United States; Philadelphia Association for Cooperative Enterprise PACE; Industrial Cooperative Association ICA
- An assessment of program related investments use of social financial intermediaries, 1981 Aug. (Reports 011449), BDM Corporation (Box 483)
  Evaluates the activities of five intermediary organizations. Includes: 4-part Appendix entitled "Investing in Financial Intermediaries--a Concept Paper for the Ford Foundation" and a bibliography.
  Small business -- Finance -- United States; Minority business enterprises -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Program-related investments; Social action -- United States; Cooperative Assistance Fund; Minority Equity Capital Corporation MECCO; Minority Contractors Assistance Project MCAP; Syndicated Communications, Inc. (SYNCOM); Urban National Corporation
- Research reports on sociology and political science, 1969-1982, 1980-1982 (bulk) 1 of 3 (Reports 011450-001), Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences FLACSO; Escuela Latinoamericana de Sociología; Consejo Latinoamericano de Ciencias Sociales; ELAS-FLACSO
  Contains bibliographies, annual program activity reports, grantee reports to the Foundation, research studies, conference proceedings (esp. CLACSO), resolutions concerning governance, and information bulletins.
  3 archives boxes (3 linear ft. containing approx. 55 items).
  Sociology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Latin America; Political science -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Latin America; Sociology -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Latin America; Political science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Latin America; Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences FLACSO; Escuela Latinoamericana de Sociología; Consejo Latinoamericano de Ciencias Sociales; ELAS-FLACSO; Programa de Estudios Conjuntos sobre Integración Económica Latinoamericana
- Research reports on sociology and political science, 1969-1982, 1980-1982 (bulk) 2 of 3 (Reports 011450-002)
- Research reports on sociology and political science, 1969-1982, 1980-1982 (bulk) 3 of 3 (Reports 011450-003)
- Boletin Bibliographico 1981, no.1 (Reports 011450-004) (Box 484)
  International Division/Latin America and the Caribbean;Developing Countries Program/Latin America and the Caribbean;International Division/Latin America and the Caribbean;Developing Countries Program/Latin America and the Caribbean
  06800796
  Sociology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Latin America; Political science -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Latin America; Sociology -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Latin America; Political science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Latin America; FLACSO (Organization). Sede Académica de México; Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences (FLACSO)
- Boletin Bibliographico 1981, no.2 (Reports 011450-005) (Box 484)
  FLACSO (Organization). Sede Académica de México; Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences (FLACSO)
- Boletin Bibliographico 1981, no.3 (Reports 011450-006) (Box 484)
- Boletin Bibliographico 1982, no.3, Septiembre - Diciembre (Reports 011450-007) (Box 484)
- Bolletin Informativo no.3, (Septeiembre-Diciembre) (Reports 011450-008), 1980 (Box 484)
- Informe de Actividades (Reports 011450-009), 1980 (Box 484)
- Informe de Actividades, 1981 no.1, Enero-Abril (Reports 011450-010) (Box 484)
- Informe de Actividades, 1981 no.2, Mayo-Agosto (Reports 011450-011) (Box 484)
- Informe de Actividades, 1981 no.3, Septiembre-Diciembre (Reports 011450-012) (Box 484)
- Informe de Actividades, 1982 no.3, Septiembre-Diciembre (Reports 011450-013) (Box 484)
- Contribuciones, numero 2: La destruccion del empleo y la logica contemporanea del trabajo, Agosto 1980. (Reports 011450-014), Schwember, Herman (Box 484)
- Contribuciones, numero 4: Sartre y Rousseau, Diciembre (Reports 011450-015), 1980; Pozo M., Hernán (Box 484)
- Contribuciones, numero 5: Empleo, migracion rural y estructura productiva agricola, Tomo 1, Marzo (Reports 011450-016), 1981; Aranda, Ximena (Box 484)
- Contribuciones, numero 5: Empleo, migracion rural y estructura productiva agricola, Tomo 2, Marzo (Reports 011450-017), 1981; Aranda, Ximena (Box 484)
- Contribuciones, numero 6: Por una interpretacion revisionista de la historia del movimiento obrero europeo, Mayo (Reports 011450-018), 1981; Paramio, Ludolfo (Box 484)
- Contribuciones, numero 7: La situacion actual del municipio chileno y el problema de la 'municipalizacion', Julio (Reports 011450-019), 1981; Pozo M., Hernán (Box 484)
- Contribuciones, numero 8: Reforma y contrapreforma universitarias en America Latina: Un caso significativo, Agosto (Reports 011450-020), 1981; Scherz, Luis (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 5: La propia educacion y la educacion de los demas, Agosto (Reports 011450-021), 1980; Flisfisch, Angel (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 6: Conciencia de clase: 1 Problemas de la ontologia marxista, Octubre (Reports 011450-022), 1980; Brunner, José Joaquín (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 7: La formacion de la conciencia feminista en Chile, Octubre (Reports 011450-023), 1980; Kirkwood, Julieta (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 10: El proyecto neoconservador y la democracia, Marzo (Reports 011450-024), 1981; Lechner, Norbert, 1939-2004 (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 11: Opciones politicas en America Latina. Comentario critico a la propuesta del Dr. Prebisch, Marzo (Reports 011450-025), 1981; Faletto, Enzo (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 12: Transformacion social y refundacion politica. Notas sobre problems de la alternativa en el capitalismo autoritario, Marzo (Reports 011450-026), 1981; Garretón Merino, Manuel A. (Manuel Antonio) (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 13: El fundamento racional de la accion y la libertad del otro, Abril (Reports 011450-027), 1981; Flisfisch, Angel (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 14: Burocracia y estado en America Latina, Abril (Reports 011450-028), 1981; Faletto, Enzo (Box 484)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 15: Acerca de la razon de estado, Julio (Reports 011450-029), 1981; Lechner, Norbert, 1939-2004 (Box 485)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 16: Notas acerca de la idea del reforzamiento de la sociedad civil, Agosto (Reports 011450-030), 1981; Flisfisch, Angel (Box 485)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 17: Cultura y desarrollo: Notas a proposito de Weber, el mercado y el autoritarismo, Septeiembre (Reports 011450-031), 1981; Brunner, José Joaquín (Box 485)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 18: La reinsercion de America Latina en el marco estrategio mundial, Agosto (Reports 011450-032), 1981; Varas, Augusto (Box 485)
- Materiales de Discusion, no. 29: Informe sobre el seminario "Intelectuales, universidad y sociedad" organizado for FLACSO en Santiago de Chile, 17-19 de Mayo (Reports 011450-033), 1982; Brunner, José Joaquín; Flisfisch, Angel (Box 485)
- Documento de Trabajo, no. 94: Los temas de democracia y libertad en Jose Medina Echavarria. Vigencia y contextos, Septeiembre (Reports 011450-034), 1980; Faletto, Enzo (Box 485)
- Documento de Trabajo, no. 97: Algunas caracteristicas de la base social del partido socialista y del partico comunista, 1958 (Reports 011450-035), 1980; Faletto, Enzo (Box 485)
- Documento de Trabajo, no. 94: En torno a la discussion de los nuevos regimenes autoritarios en America Latina, Septiembre (Reports 011450-036), 1980; Garretón Merino, Manuel A. (Manuel Antonio) (Box 485)
- Documento de Trabajo, no. 99: State crisis, arms race and disarmament in Latin America (Reports 011450-037), 1980; Varas, Augusto (Box 485)
- Documento de Trabajo, no. 100: Foreign policy and national security doctrines (Reports 011450-038), 1980; Varas, Augusto (Box 485)
- Documento de Trabajo, no. 101: Las nuevas relaciones de poder en America Latina: escernarios y prospectiva (Reports 011450-039), 1980; Varas, Augusto (Box 485)
- Documento de Trabajo, no. 102: Desarrollo y reproduccion de las fuerza de trabajo, Diciembre (Reports 011450-040), 1980; Aldunate B., Adolfo (Box 485)